lovefilm.com 2010-08-11

# LOVEFiLM | Privacy Policy

Amended 5th November 2008. Show earlier amendments from 21st June 2008

We wanted to let you know of a change to the Lovefilm group. With effect from 1 November 2008, your contract and account information were transferred from Lovefilm International Limited to Lovefilm UK Limited. Lovefilm UK Limited is another member of the Lovefilm group of companies. Don’t worry, everything else stays the same and you don’t have to do anything. We have made the small changes necessary to our Terms and Conditions and Privacy Policy to reflect this transfer. 

LOVEFiLM (a trading name of LOVEFiLM UK Limited) recognises that your privacy is very important to you and that it is your right to control your personal information. We know that providing personal information is an act of trust and we take that trust seriously. LOVEFiLM will _never_ sell, rent or, except as set out in this Privacy Policy, otherwise disclose any of your personal information, including your Email address, to any third party without your consent. Unless you give us specific consent to act otherwise, the following policies will govern how LOVEFiLM handles the personal information that you provide to us.

This Privacy Policy sets out:

  * Collection and use of information
  * Information storage
  * Information sharing and disclosure
  * Security and prevention against loss, misuse or alteration of information
  * Your ability to edit and cancel your account
  * Changes to this Privacy Policy
  * Contact details

This Privacy Policy is deemed to be incorporated into the Website Terms and Conditions, which you should read together with this Privacy Policy. Capitalised words used but not defined in this Privacy Policy have the meaning given to them in the Terms and Conditions.

### Collection and use of information

If you do not register as a Member of LOVEFiLM, the information we collect from you is limited. We log your IP address in order to help diagnose problems with our servers, administer this Website and track usage statistics. Your IP address may vary each time you visit, or it may be the same, depending on the type of internet connection. Either way, it would be extremely difficult for us to identify you through your IP address, and we make no attempt to do so. If you reach this Website by clicking on a link or advertisement on another website, then we also log that information. All of this information is collected and used only in aggregate; that is, it entered into our database, where we can use it to generate overall reports on our visitors, but not reports about individual visitors.

If you choose to register as a Member of LOVEFiLM, you will be able to take advantage of all of the features of this Website.

LOVEFiLM collects some or all of the personally identifiable information set out below when you subscribe to the LOVEFiLM serviceregister as a Member of LOVEFiLM, when you access and use this Website and/or when you use LOVEFiLM's products and/or services. The information we collect will vary depending on the circumstances, e.g., if you use one of our rental services packages or download film or TV content, we will collect most of this information. If you simply use some of our services (such as writing a review or entering a competition) we may only collect more limited information.

**What we collect**

  * Nickname
  * Full name
  * Email address
  * Address
  * Telephone number
  * Mobile telephone number (optional)
  * Credit Payment Card type
  * Credit Payment Card number
  * Credit Payment Card expiry date
  * Gender
  * Date of Birth
  * MoviesInformation about DVDs or games you have rented or would like to rent
  * Movies you would like to rentInformation about films you have downloaded or would like to download
  * Your movie Your DVD, game or download ratings
  * Your movie User Material you submit (e.g., your DVD, game or download reviews, user collections, quiz and other user submissions)
  * Information you submit for your User Profile

**How we use it**

  * To check that a Credit payment card is valid
  * To pay your account
  * To send you DVDs or games you would like to rent or films you would like to download
  * To recommend other movies DVDs or games you may like to rent or films you would like to download
  * To display your favourites list to others
  * To communicate with you regarding your Membership, account or purchase of LOVEFiLM's products or services -related matters
  * To provide you with order and billing history information
  * To establish rental trends in order to recommend other DVDs or games you may like to rent or films you may like to download
  * To contact you about the products and/or services on this Website in which you have expressed an interest
  * To display your User Profile to others users of this Website (in accordance with your security settings)
  * To email you offers, news and information (in accordance with your email communications preferences, which you can access through "My account" section)
  * To send you samples of, or marketing materials relating to, third party products or services which we believe may be of interest to you. Such materials may accompany the discs you have selected to rent, or may be sent by us separately. Please note that at no time is it necessary for us to provide your personally identifiable information to third parties in order to send you these materials

To improve services and enhance personalisation, we may periodically obtain information about you from other third party sources from whom we have lawfully obtained this data and add it to your registration information. Additionally, authorised LOVEFiLM personnel may update your registration information to accurately reflect any new information included in any communications received from you.

### Information storage

All information you provide to us is stored in the UK only on secure servers that are protected in secure facilites including firewall protection and located in those countries that form part of the European Economic Area or are considered to provide adequate protection for personal information under the European Union Data Protection Directive (95/46/EC).

### Cookies

LOVEFiLM uses cookies to help speed up the login process and for security purposes. A cookie is a small amount of data that is sent to your web browser from a web server and stored on your computer.

LOVEFiLM may store up to two types of cookie on your computer:

LOVEFiLM stores a cookie on your computer containing a unique ID is stored in a _permanent_ cookie so that you do not need to retype information every time you visit our this Website. This expires 14 days after the last time you use this Website.

Your web browser's session identification is stored in a _temporary_ cookie to help prevent unauthorised use of your account.

More detailed information on cookies may can generally be found in the "help" (or similar) section of your Internet web browser.

### Information sharing and disclosure

LOVEFiLM is committed to protecting your personal information. We will not disclose your personally identifiable information to third parties without your consent except:

  1. Where LOVEFiLM is required by law to disclose information to third parties;
  2. Where the disclosure is necessary for the performance of our operations (eg. mail delivery, hosting services, protecting us from fraud, and payment of your account); or
  3. LOVEFiLM buys or sells subsidiaries or business units. in connection with a corporate transaction, such as a sale, merger, consolidation or asset sale, or an internal reoganisation, or in the unlikely event of an insolvency. If such a transaction or event required the transfer of customer information, then that information would be one of the transferred assets, but would remain subject to the commitments made in any pre-existing Privacy Policy or equivalent.

We also may share your personal information with third parties (ie agents or sub-contractors) specifically engaged by LOVEFiLM to provide services to us, in which case we will require those parties to keep that information confidential and secure and to use it solely for the purpose of providing the specified services to us.

Companies and individuals registered in the LOVEFiLM Affiliate Program receive aggregate information about customers that they direct to LOVEFiLM through links on their websites. No personally identifiable information is provided to affiliate members; the information collected from our affiliates is used strictly for the affiliates program and will not be used for general marketing purposes.

LOVEFiLM also provides analyses of our customers in the aggregate to prospective partners, advertisers, movie distributors and other third parties. We do this so that we and our business partners can understand you better, and so we can keep bringing you first-rate services. We may also disclose, on an anonymous basis, literal statements made by our customers. At no time, however, will we disclose personal information about specific customers.

Linked websites are not under the control of LOVEFiLM and we are not responsible for the conduct of companies linked to our this Website. Before disclosing your personal information on any other website we advise you to examine their its terms and conditions of use and privacy policy.

As a subscriberPlease note that you have certain rights under the Data Protection Act 1998. You have including  the right to be told what personal information we hold about you, on our database to correct errors in that information and to prevent LOVEFiLM from using your personal information for direct marketing purposes. Should you wish to exercise that  these rights, or if you have any questions concerning the LOVEFiLM privacy policy please write to us at: LOVEFiLM, c/o LOVEFiLM UK Limited, No 9, 6 Portal Way, London W3 6RU. the contact details below.

### Security and prevention against loss, misuse or alteration of information

LOVEFiLM has implemented technology and security features, as well as strict internal guidelines, to safeguard the privacy of your personal information from unauthorised access or improper use. We will continue to enhance our security procedures as new technology becomes available.

For transmitting your personal information to us, we use a secure server with a 128256-bit SSL certificate from Verisign Thwate which encrypts all of your personal information. This encryption process ensures that the information you give us is protected against unauthorised use.

While we make every effort to ensure that your information is secure on our system, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, we cannot guarantee the security of any information you transmit to us, and you do so at your own risk.

Your LOVEFiLM account information is password-protected for your privacy and security. You can play an important role in keeping your personal information secure by maintaining the confidentiality of your password used on the LOVEFiLM website. We recommend that you change your password from time to time for additional security. Please advise us immediately if there is any unauthorised use of your account by any other Internet user or any other breach of security.

Access authorisation is granted only to key LOVEFiLM (LOVEFiLM UK Limited.) staff only and to our agents or subcontractors if necessary for the performance of our operations or for them to provide services to us. Any information accessed by those agents or subcontractors is required to be kept confidential and secure and is not permitted to be used for any purpose except to provide their services to us.

Backups are run to prevent loss of information, and our Internet servers are housed in secure facilities.

### Your ability to edit and cancel your account

You can access "My account" section from every page on this Website to update and correct the personal details that we gathered when you  subscribed  registered. You must be logged in to access this information. All information is password-protected so no one can access the information but you.

If you decide to cancel your LOVEFiLM subscription, your account will be deactivated immediately once we have received back all the discs that you have rented. However we are required to may retain your information for accounting and taxation business, operational and administrative purposes and in accordance with applicable laws.

### Changes to this Privacy Policy

From time to time, LOVEFiLM will review and may edit this policy in accordance with potential changes to our business and as required by law. LOVEFiLM reserves the right to change its Privacy Policy at any time.This Privacy Policy may be amended in accordance with paragraph 1.2 of our Terms and Conditions (of which this Privacy Policy forms part).

### LOVEFiLM's contact details

All correspondence to LOVEFiLM regarding this Privacy Policy should be addressed to:

(Attention: Privacy Officer)   
LOVEFiLM UK Limited  
No 9   
6 Portal Way   
London W3 6RU   
United Kingdom   
Email: [support@lovefilm.com](mailto:support@lovefilm.com)
